Guide to the Meyer Family Papers SC0187
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Meyer Family papers
1850-1971
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Buck, Alice Meyer
Meyer family.
SC0187
3.5 Linear Feet
no content
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Biography / Administrative History
A native Californian, J. Henry Meyer was a successful San Francisco businessman. He was an executive, a banker, and served on the boards of many companies including Wells Fargo Bank, the Spring Valley Water Company, and the California Street Cable Railroad Company. In 1878 he married Eugenie Hillegass of Berkeley. Together they had three children: Eugenie Olga, Alice, and Charles. Alice graduated from Stanford University in 1905 with a degree in English. Charles also received his degree from Stanford University in chemical engineering in 1917.
The Meyers were generous supporters of Stanford University. J. Henry Meyer donated funds towards the Lane Medical Library building and endowed library book funds. Meyer's daughters Eugenie and Alice, along with Alice's husband Frank E. Buck continued his tradition of generous support to Stanford University. They established an endowed professorship in the Graduate School of Business, donated a collection of valuable Western Americana from Mr. Meyer's library, and established the J. Henry Meyer Memorial Library. The Meyer-Buck House was built in 1920 and later willed to Stanford by Meyer's daughters.
Scope and Content of Collection
Series I includes memorial resolutions, correspondence, and documents pertaining to Meyer family properties and business interests such as deeds, abstracts of title, and stock certificates. There are also many Meyer family photographs including studio portraits, candid shots of family and friends taken at the Meyer/Buck estate, and several shots of Frank E. Buck's jade collection donated by Alice Meyer Buck to the Stanford Museum (Cantor Arts Center) in 1978. Series II consists of drawings of the Meyer-Buck estate.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged in two series:
SERIES I - Papers
SERIES II - Meyer-Buck Estate Drawings
Separated Materials
Newspapers Discarded: San Francisco Chronicle, 12 September 1955; San Francisco Examiner, 12 September 1955; San Jose News, 3 April 1975 (pp. 5-6); San Jose News, 5 April 1975 (pp. 1-2).
Photoprints.; architectural drawings (visual works); Deeds.; Buck family.; Buck, Alice Meyer; Buck, Frank E.; Meyer family.; Buck, Alice Meyer; Myers family.; Meyer, J. Henry (John Henry); Meyer, J. Henry (John Henry); Meyer family.; Buck, Frank E. (Frank Eugene)
- Papers, 1850-1971; Series 1
  - Abstract of Title to a portion of Block 148, Oakland, for Borel & Co. [bound], 1822-1903 (Box 1)
  - Abstract of Title and Certificate of Search to part of 50 Vara lot #264. Made at the request of C.H.S. Meyer [bound], 22 January 1847-1898 (Box 1)
  - Abstract of Title and Certificate of Search to part of 50 Vara lot #897. Made at the request of C.H.S. Meyer [bound], 1850-1903 (Box 1)
  - Deed to Elkhorn Ranch [bound], 1852-1905 (Box 2)
  - Abstract of Title - Eugene Avy Tract [bound], 1900 (Box 2)
  - Loose items from Avy Tract Abstract of Title, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Abstract of Title - Rancho De Las Pulgas [bound], 1904 (Box 2)
  - Rancho De Las Pulgas Maps, undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Property of J. Henry Meyer - J. Henry Meyer vs. John Freuler - Estate of Antoine Borel [bound], 1915-1916 (Box 2)
  - J. Henry Meyer - Oceano Ranch - Deed description and plat of the Coleman Tract in lots 123, 125 & 126 [bound], 1915 (Box 2)
  - Building Permits, Landscaping/Pool Expenses, 1952, 1958, undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Stock Certificates - J.H. Meyer & Co. [bound], 1916 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cost of Securities - J. Henry Meyer [bound], 1916-1922 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Maps & Drawings of J.H. Meyer's Elkhorn property in Monterey County, undated (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Drawings for cow barn and milk house, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Handwritten history about Charles H. T. Meyer, undated (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Handwritten history about Marguerite Julia Meyer, undated (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Stanford University Commencement Program, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Stanford University Diploma - Alice Marie Meyer, 1905 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Stanford University Diploma - Charles Hillegass Meyer, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Red Cross France Certificate & Correspondence - J. Henry Meyer, 1917, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Prayer Card for Madame Louise Meyer, 1937 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Bookplate - Bertha Berner, undated (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence (Miscellaneous), undated (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - J. Henry Meyer to Antoine Borel re Earthquake, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Between J. E. Wallace Sterling & Alice Meyer Buck re Meyer Library, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Handwritten remembrance, "Story of Ralph [K. Davies]," by Louise Davies, circa 1971 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Memorial Service for Ralph K. Davies, 1971 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - "Reminisces of Alice Meyer Buck," by Dorothy Lennon, undated (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Clippings, 1955-1976 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Memorial Resolution - J. Henry Meyer - California Street Cable Railroad Company, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Memorial Resolution - J. Henry Meyer - California Central Creameries, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Memorial Resolution - J. Henry Meyer - Wells Fargo, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Memorial Resolution - J. Henry Meyer - Coast Counties Gas & Electric, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Memorial Resolution - J. Henry Meyer - Spring Valley Water Company, 1921 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Invitation to Congressional Country Club - J. Henry Meyer, 1922 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Certificate - Frank Eugene Buck - In Appreciation - Mills College Trustee, 1946-1950 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Retirement Resolution - Frank Eugene Buck - Golden State Company, 1948 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous Resolutions - Frank Eugene Buck: (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Tamarack Mutual Co., 1949
  - Pacific Mutual Life Insurance Co., 1949
  - Photograph Album - Frank Eugene Buck - Dedication of Pacific Gas & Electric Pittsburg Steam Plant, 1954 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Memorial Resolution - Frank Eugene Buck - Pacific Gas & Electric, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Memorial Resolution - Frank Eugene Buck - Bank of California, 1959 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Certificate of Appreciation - Frank and Alice Buck - PA Medical Research Foundation, undated (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Memorial Resolution - Eugenie Meyer - Wells Fargo, 1918 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - J. Henry Meyer: (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Certificate - American Field Service in France, undated
  - Memorial Resolution - Bankers' Investment Company, undated
  - Memorial Resolution - Union Trust Company, 1921
  - Photograph Album - Stanford University & other, undated (Box 9)
  - Photograph Album - Vacation, undated (Box 9)
  - Photograph Album - Vacation, undated (Box 9)
  - Photograph Album - Vacation, undated (Box 9)
  - J. Henry Meyer, undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - J. Henry Meyer & Mrs. Eugenie Hillegass Meyer, 1878, undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Mrs. Eugenie Hillegass Meyer, undated (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Mrs. Eugenie Hillegass Meyer & baby, undated (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Eugenie Olga Meyer & Alice Meyer, undated (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Eugenie Olga, Alice Meyer, and Charles Hillegass Meyer, undated (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Charles Hillegass Meyer, October 1894, undated (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Charles Hillegass Meyer, undated (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Charles Hillegass Meyer, November 1896 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Charles Hillegass Meyer, November 1896 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Charles Hillegass Meyer, undated (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Alice Meyer Buck, undated (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Alice Meyer Buck, undated (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Alice Meyer Buck with Jade Pieces donated to Stanford Museum [including appraisals], circa 1978 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Meyer-Buck Estate & other properties, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Meyer-Buck Estate & other properties, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Flowers, Landscaping [including slides and negatives], undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Meyer/Buck Family - miscellaneous gatherings, undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Meyer/Buck Family - miscellaneous, mostly vacation, undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Framed Photographs, undated (Box 11)
  - Framed Photographs, undated (Box 12)
  - 16mm color film "Mr. F. Buck's Home,", April 1955 (Box 13)
  - Leica storage box with 18 rolls of negatives from a trip: (Box 13)
  - Roll 1 NG, 10 January 1936
  - Roll 2 Ship, 20 January 1936
  - Roll 3 Rio, undated
  - Roll 4 Rio, St. Helena, 29 January 1936
  - Roll 5 Capetown, undated
  - Roll 6 Victoria Falls, 10 February 1936
  - Roll 7 Krueger Park, 12 February 1936
  - Roll 8 Madagascar, undated
  - Roll 9 Ceylon, undated
  - Roll 10 Ceylon, India, undated
  - Roll 11 Bali, undated
  - Roll 12 Bangkok, undated
  - Roll 13 Angkor (No. 1), undated
  - Roll 14 Angkor (No. 2), undated
  - Roll 15 Seychelles, Bombay, undated
  - Roll 16 Agra, undated
  - Roll 17 Delhi, undated
  - Roll 18 Benares, undated
  - Roll (Empty), undated
  - Roll (Possibly shot but not developed), undated
- Meyer-Buck Estate Drawings, Series 2
  Scope and Contents
  Drawings 1 through 39 are by Bakewell & Brown Architects, 1920, except where prefaced with PMC - Pacific Manufacturing Company. Drawing 40 is a survey of the residence grounds by D. Bromfield, 1908. Numbers 3, 5B, 13B, 17, 19, 21, and 22, have been flattened; the remainder are rolled. All of them are now in map case storage.
  - Full size details of French windows (#503) (Folder 1)
  - Full size details of main stairs (#527) (Folder 2 a,b,c)
  - Three-quarter scale detail of main stairs (#106) (Folder 3)
  - PMC. Servants dining room pantry kitchen and butlers pantry cases (#15) (Folder 4)
  - Full size details of living room and dining room (#524) (Folder 5 a,b,c)
  - Full size detail of stair halls (#526) (Folder 6 a,b,c)
  - PMC. First and second floor frames (#2) (Folder 7)
  - PMC. Larder cases (#17) (Folder 8)
  - Full size detail of marble slab under toilet (#519) (Folder 9 a,b,c)
  - Full size detail of terrace balustrade (#521) (Folder 10)
  - Full size detail of mantel (#528) (Folder 11)
  - PMC. Library [full scale misc. details] (#21) (Folder 12)
  - Half full size detail interior of bay windows (#525) (Folder 13 a,b,c)
  - PMC. Living and dining room [full size details] (#23) (Folder 14)
  - Full size details of basement frames (#501) (Folder 15)
  - Full size detail of library (#522) (Folder 16 a,b,c)
  - PMC. Porch sash and louver frames (#3) (Folder 17)
  - PMC. Bay templet [sic] (#1) (Folder 18)
  - Full size detail of balconies (#508) (Folder 19)
  - Full size detail of double hung windows (#502) (Folder 20)
  - Full size detail of main cornice, servants' wing (#507) (Folder 21)
  - Spacing of balusters on terrace [partial plan of terrace] (#109) (Folder 22)
  - Mantel in bedroom no. 4 (#531) (Folder 23 a,b,c)
  - Full size details of vents in roof (#505) (Folder 24)
  - PMC. Balconys [sic], details (#5) (Folder 25)
  - Full size detail mantel in living room (#529) (Folder 26 a,b,c)
  - PMC. Main cornice (#4) (Folder 27)
  - Full size detail of main cornice (#506) (Folder 28)
  - Developed full size detail center panel of balcony, north elevation (#511) (Folder 29 a,b)
  - Developed side panels balcony, north elevation (#512) (Folder 30 a,b)
  - Full size detail large panels (occurs under windows) balcony, east elevation; also typical ironwork for small balconies second floor (#513) (Folder 31 a,b)
  - End panels for balcony, east elevation; small panels for balcony, east elevation (#514) (Folder 32 a,b)
  - Full size detail of bracket under main balcony (#515) (Folder 33 a,b)
  - Full size detail center panel of iron rail on bay windows (#509) (Folder 34 a,b)
  - Developed curved panels bay windows (#510) (Folder 35 a,b)
  - Full size detail of small curved bracket and guard rail for window in bedroom no. 1; also scale details of bracket spacing (#516) (Folder 36)
  - Full size detail of entrance vestibule (#520) (Folder 37)
  - PMC. Dormer frames (#7) (Folder 38)
  - PMC. Library, details (#20) (Folder 39)
  - Map of Residence Grounds of Henry Meyer, Menlo Park; surveyed by D. Bromfield, October 1908. (Van Dyke reproducible) [this is a negative format drawing] (Folder 40)
- Additional Papers, Accession ARCH-2017-241
  - Typescript about Meyer-Buck House, Mrs. Buck, Alice Buck, and Olga Meyer. (Box 1)